
const quiz2 = [
  {//1
    question: 'Which vehicles should use the left-hand lane on a three-lane motorway?',
    options: ["A. Any vehicle that’s not overtaking", 'B. Large vehicles only', 'C. Emergency vehicles only', 'D Slow vehicles only'],
    answer: "A. Any vehicle that’s not overtaking",
  },
  {//2
    question: "You're travelling along a motorway. Where would you find a crawler or climbing lane?",
    options: ['A. On a steep gradient', 'B. Before a service area', 'C. Before a junction', 'D. Along the hard shoulder'],
    answer: 'A. On a steep gradient',
  },
  {//3
    question: 'When are you allowed to stop on a motorway?',
    options: ['A. When you need to walk and get fresh air', 'B. When you wish to pick up hitchhikers', "C. When you're signalled to do so by traffic signals", 'D. When you need to use a mobile telephone'],
    answer: "C. When you're signalled to do so by traffic signals",
  },
  {//4
    question: 'When would you use the right-hand lane on a three-lane motorway?',
    options: ["A. When you're turning right", "B. When you're overtaking", "C. When you're travelling above the speed limit", "D. When you're trying to save fuel"],
    answer: "B. When you're overtaking",
  },
  {//5
    question: 'When may you stop on a motorway?',
    options: ['A. If you have to read a map', "B. When you're tired and need a rest", 'C. If your mobile phone rings', 'D. In an emergency or breakdown'],
    answer: 'D. In an emergency or breakdown',
  },
{//6
    question: 'You have stopped in an emergency area. What must you do before you rejoin the carriageway?',
    options: ['A. Use the emergency telephone', "B. Give an arm signal as you are moving off", "C. Switch on your vehicle's headlights", 'D. Move away with your hazard lights on'],
    answer: 'A. Use the emergency telephone',
  },
  {//7
    question: 'What should you do immediately after joining a motorway?',
    options: ['A. Try to overtake', "B. Re-adjust your mirrors", "C. Position your vehicle in the centre lane", 'D. Stay in the left-hand lane'],
    answer: 'D. Stay in the left-hand lane',
  },
  {//8
    question: "You're travelling along a motorway. When are you allowed to overtake on the left?",
    options: ['A. When you can see well ahead that the hard shoulder is clear', "B. When the traffic in the right-hand lane is signalling right", "C. When you warn drivers behind by signalling left"," D. When in queues and traffic to your right is moving more slowly than you are"],
    answer: " D. When in queues and traffic to your right is moving more slowly than you are",
  },
   {//9
    question: "What's the national speed limit for a car or motorcycle on a motorway?",
    options: ['A. 50 mph', "B. 60 mph", "C. 70 mph "," D. 80 mph"],
    answer: "C. 70 mph ",
  },
    {//10
    question: "How should you use the lanes on a motorway?",
    options: ['A. Use the lane that has the least traffic', "B. Keep to the left-hand lane unless you're overtaking", "C. Overtake using the lane that’s clearest "," D. Stay in one lane until you reach your exit"],
    answer: "B. Keep to the left-hand lane unless you're overtaking",
  },
  {//11
   question: "How should you rejoin the motorway after a breakdown on the hard shoulder?",
    options: ['A. Build up speed on the hard shoulder before looking for a safe gap in the traffic', "B. Move straight out into the left-hand lane as you are not allowed to drive on the hard shoulder", "C. Wait until a vehicle in the left-hand lane signals to you that it's safe to rejoin "," D. Keep your hazard lights flashing until you have safely rejoined the carriageway"],
    answer: "A. Build up speed on the hard shoulder before looking for a safe gap in the traffic",
  },
  {//12
   question: "What should you do while you're driving or riding along a motorway?",
    options: ['A. Look much further ahead than you would on other roads', "B. Travel much faster than you would on other roads", "C. Maintain a shorter separation distance than you would on other roads "," D. Concentrate more than you would on other roads"],
    answer: "A. Look much further ahead than you would on other roads",
  },
   {//13
   question: "When would you use an emergency area on a motorway?",
    options: ["A. In cases of emergency or breakdown", "B. If you think you'll be involved in a road rage incident", "C. To stop and check where you are "," D. To make a private phone call"],
    answer: "A. In cases of emergency or breakdown",
  },
  {//14
   question: "Where should you stop to rest if you feel tired while you're travelling along a motorway?",
    options: ["A. On the hard shoulder", "B. At the nearest service area", "C. On a slip road "," D. On the central reservation"],
    answer: "B. At the nearest service area",
  },
  {//15
   question: "Which vehicles are prohibited from using the motorway?",
    options: ["A. Powered mobility scooters", "B. Motorcycles over 50 cc", "C. Double-deck buses "," D. Cars with automatic transmission"],
    answer: "A. Powered mobility scooters",
  },
 {//16
   question: "What should you do when you're approaching roadworks on a motorway?",
    options: ["A. Speed up to clear the area quickly", "B. Always use the hard shoulder", "C. Obey the speed limit "," D. Stay very close to the vehicle in front"],
    answer: "C. Obey the speed limit ",
  },
{//17
   question: "Why is it particularly important to check your vehicle before making a long motorway journey?",
    options: ["A. You'll have to do more harsh braking on motorways", "B. Motorway services areas do not deal with breakdowns", "C. The road surface will wear down the tyres faster","D. Continuous high speeds increase the risk of your vehicle breaking down"],
    answer: "D. Continuous high speeds increase the risk of your vehicle breaking down",
  },
{//18
   question: "You're on a motorway. What does it mean when a red cross is displayed above the hard shoulder?",
    options: ["A. Pull up in this lane to answer your mobile phone", "B. Use this lane as a running lane", "C. This lane can be used if you need a rest","D. You must not travel in this lane"],
    answer: "D. You must not travel in this lane",
  },
  {//19
   question: "What should you do when going through a contraflow system on a motorway?",
    options: ["A. Use dipped headlights", "B. Keep a good distance from the vehicle ahead", "C. Switch lanes to keep the traffic flowing","D. Stay close to the vehicle ahead to reduce queues"],
    answer: "B. Keep a good distance from the vehicle ahead",
  },
    {//20
   question: "Where are amber reflective studs found on a motorway?",
    options: ["A. Between the hard shoulder and the carriageway", "B. Between the acceleration lane and the carriageway", "C. Between the central reservation and the carriageway","D. Between each pair of lanes"],
    answer: "C. Between the central reservation and the carriageway",
  },

];

export default quiz2;